# **Andrew Hercules**

# UX Research & Design. Digital Strategy.

Phone: 416 312 4744 | Email: andrewhercules@gmail.com | Web: andrewhercules.com

#### PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I am a Toronto-based user experience (UX) researcher and designer and digital strategist. With a diverse and transferable skillset and a range of industry experience, I support and guide organisations that want to transform their operations with technology. Applying a user-centered, co-operative design approach, I research, design, and build solutions that meet the needs of users while streamlining and improving existing organisational practices.

#### **SKILLS**

**User Experience (UX):** user research (contextual interviews, focus groups, field visits, card sorting, A/B testing, surveys, ethnographic studies, etc.); user journeys and stories; user personas; storyboarding; wireframing; prototyping; interaction design; user testing; usability testing

Web Development: JavaScript (Angular, React, jQuery); Ruby (Rails, Sinatra); HTML5; CSS3

**Digital Strategy:** content development; information architecture; competitor analysis; web/graphic design; search engine optimisation (SEO); web analytics; accessibility standards; communications and public relations; stakeholder management; digital marketing; e-commerce; m-commerce

**Tools:** MS Office; Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, InDesign, Illustrator); wireframing/prototyping software (Axure, Sketch, Keynote, InVision, Balsamiq)

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Freelance Digital Strategist**

January 2017 – present

Self-Employed / Freelance

- Provide content strategy and design services to a global direct sales company that wants to improve the communications sent to new consultants completing an initial 90-day program
- Conduct a brief research and discovery process for a financial services company and using the insights generated, create high-fidelity mockups for a new employee training mobile app

## **UX Researcher/Designer & Developer**

October 2015 – January 2017

University of London

- Designed, built, and customised institutional repositories for academic and research institutions
- Completed UX research projects that utilised a range of quantitative and qualitative research methodologies for internal and external education and research sector clients
- Created requirements documents, user journeys and personas, and user stories, and repurposed
   UX research outputs for thought leadership opportunities (e.g. presentations, white papers)
- Collaborated with colleagues to redesign the user experience and user journeys for various platforms and websites and coordinated user testing sessions to validate designs
- Hired, trained, and mentored new staff, including the team's Graduate Designer and Graduate Developer and work placement students

Deloitte Digital

- Project Aztec (one of Europe's largest insurance companies):
  - Collaborated with colleagues across multiple business units to build a proof of concept application that provided existing insurance customers with online robo-advice
  - Created static interface mockups and user stories and transformed them into an interactive single page application using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript (AngularJS)
- Project IM Mobile TfL (Transport for London):
  - Coordinated on-site user testing sessions and feedback sessions to promote a culture of transparency, accountability, and user-centred design
  - Wrote recommendation reports based on research findings for senior stakeholders
  - Created design patterns that were used for subsequent mobile app development projects
  - Worked with TfL colleagues to develop and test user-friendly training materials
  - Developed static mockups with Photoshop and Illustrator

# **Freelance Digital Consultant**

June 2014 – April 2015

Self-Employed / Freelance

- Provided branding, photography, and staffing consultancy services to Minds Matter Magazine, the first student-led magazine about mental health at the University of Toronto Scarborough
- Worked with the University of Toronto's Department of Arts, Culture and Media to develop shortand medium-term marketing strategies and succession planning documents
- Collaborated with a start-up law firm in Toronto to develop content marketing strategies
- Worked with small boutique consultancies looking to establish and curate their digital footprint

# **Communications Coordinator and Front-End Developer**

October 2011 – September 2014

University of Toronto – Department of Arts, Culture and Media

- Designed a range of print and electronic promotional materials and ensured design work was in line with university and departmental trademark and branding protocols
- Coordinated all media and stakeholder relations to increase the visibility of departmental events
- Acted as the lead design and research consultant on a large-scale project to redevelop the departmental website and transition it from basic HTML/CSS to the Drupal CMS framework
  - Engaged in competitor analysis, a comprehensive information architecture audit, and a review of existing content prior to the development of the site
  - Coordinated user research and testing sessions with staff, faculty, and student to uncover user needs and to solicit feedback on proposed website changes
- Developed email newsletters with MailChimp and HTML/CSS and implemented content and layout strategies, which led to consistent open rates above 25%
- Produced annual reports and funding applications, which resulted in \$45,000 CAD in funding over three years (2012-2014) to support and enhance departmental events and programming
- Hired and supervised 3-6 casual staff members working in design/technical/website positions

#### **Freelance Writer / Content Producer**

2003 – present

A Dose of Andrew Media

- Researched, wrote, and content for TheHiringHotline.com, a website with student job listings
- Wrote news, feature, and commentary articles for various publications including the Toronto Star, Toronto Sun, Scarborough Mirror, 24 Hours, and InsideToronto.com
- Researched news and feature stories for Network Europe, a pan-European radio program, and managed multimedia and interactive content hosted on the show's website

#### **PORTFOLIO**

For a complete version of my portfolio, please visit <a href="http://andrewhercules.com/#portfolio">http://andrewhercules.com/#portfolio</a>.

*UX Research & Design* 

#### **Bloom Research & Design Project**

Bloom is a learning platform used by more than three million users across the United Kingdom. As the co-lead researcher, I utilised a variety of quantitative and qualitative research methods to generate insights for personas, user journeys, low-fidelity mockups, and white papers.

## **Fast-Add Manuscript System Project**

As the lead researcher, I explored user needs around a system used to submit manuscripts for internal review. I produced a 30-page report with <u>sample personas</u> and <u>low-fidelity wireframes</u> to demonstrate potential system design and functionality based on user needs.

#### Transport for London (TfL) Connectivity Status Design Pattern

As part of a cross-functional team, I coordinated user testing sessions for existing mobile apps built by third-party suppliers. Based on user feedback, I created <u>a design pattern for connectivity</u> notifications for both tablet and smartphone devices.

Other Work

#### Personal Website - http://andrewhercules.com

I built my personal website with the Bootstrap framework, vanilla HTML/CSS, and various JavaScript libraries. I also sourced the static elements from various free vector websites and altered them to fit my personal branding.

#### Print & Digital Design Portfolio – http://bit.ly/AH-design-portfolio

This portfolio (in PDF format) contains samples of my graphic design work for both print and digital platforms along with a brief description of each project.

#### Rock, Paper, Scissors – http://ah-rps.herokuapp.com

A simple web version of the classic game Rock, Paper, Scissors that I designed and built using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Please note that the site is not responsive as the focus of the project was on integrating a JavaScript game engine with HTML and CSS.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Ongoing Professional Development**

2011 - present

UX Design for Productivity; UX & Web Design Master Course: Strategy, Design, and Development; Adobe CS6; Axure Prototyping; UX Research Methodologies; Mobile Apps: Research & Design; Ruby on Rails; Front-End Development 101; Electronic Records Management; Google Analytics; Search Engine Optimisation for Media

#### Master of Arts, Journalism & Media

August 2008 - May 2010

Aarhus University, University of Amsterdam, City University London

#### **Bachelor of Arts, Political Science**

September 2004 – June 2008